

http://stat.wvu.edu/~draffle/raffled@gmail.com|724.518.7446

# **EDUCATION**

#### **WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY**

MS IN STATISTICS

Expected Aug 2015 | Morgantown, WV

# CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE MINOR IN MATHEMATICS Grad. May 2013 | California, PA

## LINKS

Portfolio://

stat.wvu.edu/d@affle/portfolio.html

Github://

github.com/raffled/

LinkedIn://

linkedin.com/in/raffled

# SKILLS

#### **MAJOR SKILL SETS**

Data Technologies
Statistical Modeling
Multivariate Analysis
Data Mining/Machine Learning
Big Data Analytics
Software Development
Data Visualization
Text Mining
Technical Writing/Presentation

#### **TECHNOLOGIES/PLATFORMS**

Microsoft Office JMP

Hadoop/MapReduce

Linux/Unix

**RStudio** 

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Strong

R

HTML/XML

MT<sub>F</sub>X

Markdown/R Markdown

Familiar

C/C++

Java

JavaScript

LISP

Python

SQL

#### SUMMARY

I am a data scientist and statistician with a strong background in both software development and statistical analysis. My experience in teaching and research has allowed me the opportunity to not only learn and implement a variety of statistical and machine learning models, but to hone my presentation skills and work closely with experts in a variety of fields. My goal is to find a challenging position where I can solve novel problems and make data-driven policy recommendations.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY | GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

August 2013 - May 2015 | Department of Statistics | Morgantown, WV

- Work with lecturers and professors to develop teaching and evaluation strategies.
- Teach and grade for laboratory and lecture sections of undergraduate Statistics courses, where the students review concepts and get hands-on experience using Statistics to solve realistic problems.
- Work in our Statistics Tutoring Center to help students master coursework from any of our department's classes, from 100- to 400-level, in a one-on-one environment.

# WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY | GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May 2014 - Sept. 2014 | West Virginia Dialect Project | Morgantown, WV

- Consulted with linguists to helpt them evaluate and create analysis workflows.
- Cleaned, shaped, and performed Exploratory Data Analyis on large data files generated by speech-processing software (Praat).
- Built and evaluated Linear and Generalized Linear Mixed Effects models used in the investigation of sociolinguistic trends.
- Reported results in a manner accessible to wide audiences.

#### CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sept. 2010 - May 2013 | The Lexomics Project | California, PA

- Used Hierarchical Clustering algorithms to analyze works of literature for stylistic variation.
- Presented at several conferences and co-authored a paper explaining our methodology and results.

#### THE WHEATON LEXOMICS GROUP | RESEARCH INTERN

Summer 2012 | Wheaton College | Norton, MA

- Worked directly with professors of Statistics and Computer Science to develop, test, and document software for performing and visualizing cluster analysis in text mining.
- Evaluated and implemented various machine learning and statistical methods to further analyze the features that are most indicative of clustering behavior and perform cluster validation.

# AWARDS AND GRANTS

2014 Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award (WVU)

2012 Second Place - Student Scholarship and Creativity Day (CalU)

2011 Jesse B. Guttman Student Research Grant

2011 Third Place - Student Scholarship and Creativity Day (CalU)